





About Me | I am a designer and HCI researcher who crafts and prototypes ideas into interactive digital experiences across various mediums, including VR, AR, desktop video games, and mobile applications. My background in engineering and computer music provides me with balanced perspectives from an engineer, an artist, and a designer; my journey has also gradually led me to a comprehensive perspective on how to integrate graphics, sound, music, and interaction in experience design.

Education

2021 - now, University of California, Santa Cruz

Ph.D. in Computational Media | Social Emotion Lab

2018 - 2020, Stanford University

MA in Music, Science and Technology | GPA: 3.5/4.0

2014 - 2018, University of Nottingham

BEing in Electrical and Electronics Engineering | GPA: 3.9/4.0, first class

Work Experiences

June 2022 - September 2022, HCI Research Designer, Snap Research, NYC

- Explored digital handcrafting in AR for encouraging people to invest meaningful effort in digital communication. Our team productized our ideas in a Snapchat Lens called TimeCapsule.
- In the team, I served as a research designer and prototyper. I analyzed the pre-design survey to narrow down the design constraints, collaborated with a graphic designer on low/high-fidelity mockups, prototyped the experience, and delivered the prototype to the engineer, working together for the final implementation.
- Created write-ups for documenting the concept, features, and user study for the project.

January 2021 - June 2021, Game User Experience Designer, ByteDance

- Based on the needs outlined in the game designers' documents, I conceptualized and prototyped low-fidelity UX for the mobile game systems and communicated with artists to request UI art assets.
- Translated the descriptive needs from game designers into Excel tables to provide visual guidance for outsourcing artists.
- Communicated with front-end engineers to implement the prototype and also worked with FX designers for adding visual effects.

2020 - 2021, Teaching workshop @ShanghaiTech University and @Academy of Arts & Design, Tsinghua University

- At ShanghaiTech, I taught a 3-day workshop titled 'Interactive Audio-Visual Experience', primarily targeting engineering students.
- At Tsinghua Art, I co-taught a class with Fan Xiang, introducing Unity to Visual Communication students to combine their motion art with interactivity. I learned how to teach art students programming.

June 2017 - Sep 2017, Audio Prototyping Intern, Yamaha, Japan

- Our team was prototyping an All-in-one musical PA system (speaker).
- Researched similar products from competitive companies, such as JBL, Bose, and Roland.
- Learned to use SolidWorks for 3D modeling the speaker sketches provided by mechanical engineers. The 3D models were delivered to manufacturers to create a wood prototype.
- Measured the frequency response of the wood prototype and applied filters to adjust the sound features for better quality.



Design Skills

Design/Prototyping Tools

Unity, Blender, Figma, Photoshop, AfterEffect

Programming

C#, C++, Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS

Music Tools

Logic Pro X, Reaper

Interpersonal Skills

- · Communication between engineers, designers, and artists.
- Documenting and reflection.
- Being collaborative and patient.

Design Publication

[1] Chen Ji, Angela Y.H. Fan, Ella Dagan, Samir Ghosh, Yuhui Wang, and Katherine Isbister. The Cuteness Factor: An Interpretive Framework for Artists. Designers and Engineers. In Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Designing Interactive Systems Conference (DIS '23) [paper, video]

[2] Ji, Chen, and Katherine Isbister. "AR Fidget: Augmented Reality Experiences that Support Emotion Regulation through Fidgeting." CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts. 2022. [paper, video]

[3] Ji C., Nishino H. Daydream: A Healing Game for Mitigating Quarantine-induced Negative Emotions with Music Adventure. In Extended Abstracts of the 2020 Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play 2020 Nov 2 (pp. 64-67). [paper, video]